hey guys welcome to this problem we're
going to find the probability of red or
a card given this table here first thing
we can do is fill in the totals just a
little bit of addition so now probably a
red or a car there's two ways to do this
we can circle all the red stuff and
all the cars
and
just add these values up
35 + 70 + 25 + 45 these are all the
things that satisfy it and then we
divide our you might 315 because that's
the total number
so add these up
we get a 175 over 315 can reduce it so
our answers 5 nights there's one other
way we can do this and that is
probability of red
plus the probability of car
minus the probability of red and car
so we'll do that real quick to
probability of red is this total
105 over 315
plus
probability of car is this total 105
over 3 15
minus this overlap of red and car which
is 35 / 3 15 after we do the math here
we end up with 175 / 3 15 which is the
same thing we had above so our final
answer is 59 so you can do it either way
identify everything that's true for or
apply this formula hope it makes sense
to talk to soon bye
you